JOSÉ ALBERTO CASTAÑO

CONTACT

Hassocks, West Sussex BN6 8AN

((<u>)</u>) 07449482437,

j.albertocast@gmail.com

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Declarative languages HTML & CSS / Programming languages -JavaScript, Python.
- Front-End Frameworks Bootstrap, jQuery, Materializecss
- Application Process Interface
- Web Framework Flask, Django
- **Templating Engine** Jinja
- Databases MongoDB, MySQL
- Container-based cloud Platform as a **Service (PaaS)** – Heroku
- IDE's Gitpod, Replit.
- Good understanding of User Experience/User Interface
- Good knowledge of General IT Infrastructure
- New business and account management
- Negotiation skills
- Confident Communicator
- Experienced in maintaining good relationships with customers and suppliers alike
- Experienced in problem-solving and customer service issues

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, **PROFILES**

• https://github.com/JoseCastanoCoding

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- The Vinyl Aficionado (Milestone Project 1, Code Institute) Built using HTML & CSS GitHub link: https://github.com /JoseCastanoCoding/the-vinylaficionado.
- East Sussex MTB Trails (Milestone Project 2, Code Institute). Built using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. GitHub

Enthusiastic, diligent, ambitious individual looking to use and further develop my ability with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python languages in a practical and fast-paced environment.

I am currently edging the end of my studies to become a full-stack software developer with The Code Institute of Ireland, and my career goal is to assume a role which allows me to put into practice my programming skills and passion with an innovative, forward-thinking tech-company.

I have gained excellent problem-solving and customer service skills from over 6 years' experience in IT consultancy and account management roles.

I am bilingual in Spanish and English and have excellent communication skills, proficient as working as part of a team as well as on my own initiative.

EXPERIENCE

November 2017 to Current

Account Manager Trustco Plc

- Providing IT consultancy services at a pre-sales level to IT company decision makers.
- Arranging conference calls and product demonstrations between customers and technical engineers of the vendors whose technology
- Assessing the needs of potential customers in order to suggest a combination of technology and vendors to fit the requirements of the end user.
- Producing quotations via the CRM system, tracking deliveries to customers and liaising with resellers to ensure that deadlines are
- Optimised sales volume by managing accounts and building rapport,
- Ensured client satisfaction ratings by quickly offering proactive resolution ideas while driving actionable responses to questions, concerns or challenges.
- Increased revenue by obtaining and securing new accounts, while providing value-added services to existing clients.

December 2014 to November 2017

Account Manager & logistics Specialist Tomax Technology Ltd

- Drove over £400k in gross revenue in the first two years mainly based on new business accounts.
- Commercialization of Cisco networking hardware equipment as an authorised Cisco reseller.
- Managed a portfolio of domestic, European, and international
- Created and maintained contact with vendors and customers to ensure timely delivery of goods.
- Provided international paperwork such as FCC forms and commercial invoices including harmonized codes, tariff codes and product specifications.
- Knowledge of USA and Europe customs procedures.

- link: https://github.com /JoseCastanoCoding/east-sussexmtb-trails.
- Clubbing Buddy (Milestone Project 3, Code Institute) Built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python. GitHub link: https://github.com /JoseCastanoCoding /ms3-clubbing-buddy
- The Record Bloke (Personal Project in my own time, exploring new technologies) Built using Wordpress Link: https://www.therecordbloke.com/. **
- Link to all my repositories in GitHub: https://github.com /JoseCastanoCoding.

currently revamping the website!

• Developed Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) for the entire logistic department.

August 2012 to November 2014

Outward Manager Kokoba Ltd, Medicanimal Ltd

- Lead a team of more than 25 employees in developing and implemented strategy for packing and dispatch.
- Ensured that all parcels were quickly and correctly packed.
- Established a fully controlled outward mail area for the production of mail type products for all courier options.
- Key contact and liaison point for courier service providers regarding bill queries, extra collection ordering, Saturday delivery, collection arrangements and all on-going operational matters.
- Acquired knowledge of Warehouse Management System.

EDUCATION

ongoing

Diploma Full Stack Software Development Code Institute of Northern Ireland

November 2014

Award in Computerised Accounts for Business (Sage Certificate) Entry 3 Certificate in Employability Skills Certificate No.-5501255703/280 L1 Certificate in IT user skills Certificate No.-C7760075/170484 Accounting and Harrow College, Economy Business Institute

July 2010

Accounting & Balances Analysis
Accounting and Economy Business Institute (IECE), Seville

2009

Business English Certificate University Pablo de Olavide

2009

BEC preliminary Business Studies University Pablo de Olavide, Seville